Harleigh B. Trecker Papers 1986.0008
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Harleigh B. Trecker Papers
undated, 1921-1981
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1986.0008
26.9 Linear Feet
Harleigh Bradley Trecker was born 11 February 1911 in Calery, Illinois. Trecker attended George Williams College (B.S., 1934) and the University of Chicago (M.A., 1938) before embarking upon a career in social work. From 1938 until 1941, Trecker was an instructor at George Williams College and in 1941; he accepted a position at the University of Southern California. In 1951, Trecker accepted the position of Dean, School of Social Work at the University of Connecticut; a position he retained until 1968. From 1968 until his retirement in 1977, Trecker held the position of Professor of Social Work. Trecker's research focused on social work administration and boards of community service agencies. Harleigh Trecker died in 1986.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the collection was donated by Mr. Trecker circa 1986. Additional materials and plaques, diplomas, and certificates were transferred from the University of Connecticut School of Social Work Library.
Arrangement
Series I: School of Social Work Files (1936-1976) consists of the subject files that were kept by Harleigh Trecker at the University of Connecticut. The majority of the information in the series pertains to aspects of the UConn School of Social Work and is arranged alphabetically.
Series II: Writings (undated, 1939-1981) is subdivided into six sections and contains some of the books written by Trecker and a master set of his writings. The master set was compiled by Trecker and includes his speeches, articles and book reviews written between 1939 and 1971. Also included in the series are additional articles, speeches, his master's thesis and notes.
Series III: Research Studies (undated) consists of scholarly research papers and publications that were conducted either by, or under the supervision of, Harleigh B. Trecker. The studies cover a wide geographic portion of the United States.
Series IV: Research Files (undated, 1921-1964) is organized into four sections including publications, publications concerning boards of directors, bibliographic notes and newspaper clippings. The clippings cover the Newburgh affair, poverty, schools and student protests.
Series V: Framed Objects (undated, 1955) consists of photographs and a certificate.
Series VI: 1997 Addition Inventory (undated>) contains materials that were transferred to the collection at a later date.
Biography
Harleigh Bradley Trecker was born 11 February 1911, in Calery, Illinois, the son of William Henry and Henrietta Trecker. Trecker attended George Williams College (B.S., 1934) and the University of Chicago (M.S., 1938) before embarking upon a career in social work. From 1938 until 1941, Trecker was an instructor at George Williams College and in 1941; he accepted a position at the University of Southern California. In 1951, Trecker accepted the position of Dean, School of Social Work at the University of Connecticut; a position he retained until 1968. From 1968 until his retirement in 1977, Trecker held the position of Professor of Social Work.
Throughout his career, Trecker was involved in several professional societies including the National Conference on Social Welfare, National Association of Social Workers, and the Council of Social Work Education. He was active in his field as a consultant, institute leader, and lecturer, as well as being a prolific writer. He authored twenty books, some of which were translated into foreign languages. He also wrote numerous journal articles and book reviews. Trecker's research focused on social work administration and boards of community service agencies. Trecker received several awards and distinctions including a citation from the American Association of Social Workers (1951) and a certificate of recognition from the Connecticut Social Welfare Conference (1967).
Harleigh Trecker died in 1986.
Scope and Content
The collection documents the professional activities of Harleigh Trecker and includes correspondence, articles, research papers, publications, newspaper clippings, certificates and awards.
Newsletters; Speeches (documents); Interviews; Monographs; Doctoral dissertations; Bibliographies; Questionnaires; Manuals (instructional materials); Financial Records; Administrative records; Photographs; Publications (documents); Notes; Photocopies; Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence; Notebooks; Press releases; Public welfare; Social movements; Protest movements; Social work education; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Hartford (inhabited place); Trade associations; Social service; United States (nation); Education; Schools of social work; Societies; West Hartford (inhabited place); Universities and colleges; Mental retardation; Juvenile delinquency; Poverty; Prisons; Educators; Administrators; Council on Social Work Education; Connecticut Social Welfare Conference; National Social Welfare Assembly
- Series I: School of Social Work Files, undated, 1936-1976
  - Accreditation
    - Files, 1949 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Announcements, 1949, 1951 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Report of Full Accreditation, 1952 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Ad hoc committee on School Development, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Goals, 1973-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Admissions
    - Report, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Requirements, 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Statistics, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Advocacy, undated (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Alumni, 1963 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Anniversary, School of Social Work
    - 10th, 1956 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - 25th, Announcements, Convocation, Dinner, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Annual reports, 1961-1966 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Archives Instructions, undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Barrett, (Dr.)
    - First Study of the need for School of Social Work, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Memorandum on Proposed School, 1942 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Bibliography of Social Work Education, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Black experiences and Black Student Organization, undated (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Budget, 1945-1946 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Allotment, 1946-1947 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Tentative Budget, 1946-1947 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Estimated, 1948-1949 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - Manual, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Material, undated (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - State Welfare Grant, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Bureau of Social Welfare Policy Research, undated (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Case, Marjorie [first fulltime faculty appt.], 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Chronology, 1936-1950 (Box 1:, Folder 28-29)
  - Committee of Faculty Organization, undated (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - Connecticut Association of Social Work
    - Talk with Acting Dean Case, 1947 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
    - Establishment of School of Social Work, 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - Convocation, 1970-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 33-34)
  - Correspondence—American Association of Schools of Social Work, 1939-1949 (Box 1:, Folder 35-36)
  - Continuing Education, undated (Box 1:, Folder 37)
  - Cost of New Building, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
  - Credit Extension courses, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 39-40)
  - Course schedules, undated (Box 1:, Folder 41)
  - Council on Social Education, 1975-1976 (Box 1:, Folder 42)
    - Enrollment Statistics, 1951-1972 (Box 1:, Folder 43-44)
  - Current Trends in Social Work Education [Trecker], 1952 (Box 1:, Folder 45)
  - Curriculum, 1951-1977 (Box 1:, Folder 46-50)
  - Deans, 1946-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 51)
    - Dean Coleman's Instructions on Honoraria, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 52)
    - Dean Coleman's Memorandum of Goals, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 53)
  - Dedication of New Building, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 54)
  - Degrees awarded, 1948-1973 (Box 1:, Folder 55)
  - Development Plan for School, 1954-1964 (Box 1:, Folder 56)
  - Early Personal material, 1940-1959 (Box 1:, Folder 57)
  - Educational Review committee, undated (Box 1:, Folder 58)
  - Enrollment data
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 1:, Folder 59)
    - Fulltime, Part-time, Male, Female, Semester, 1946-1973 (Box 1:, Folder 60)
    - Statistics, 1946-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 61-62)
  - Extended degree students, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 63)
  - Faculty Administration Advisory committee, undated (Box 1:, Folder 64)
  - Faculty (Box not specified)
    - Advance, 1969-1970 (Box 2:, Folder 65)
    - Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 66)
    - Course Evaluations, undated (Box 2:, Folder 67)
    - Development committee, 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 68)
      - Questionnaire, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 69)
    - Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 2:, Folder 70)
      - Analyses of meeting motions, 1973-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 71)
    - Memoranda, undated (Box 2:, Folder 72-73)
    - Questionnaire, Advising Policy, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 74)
  - Federal Training grants, undated (Box 2:, Folder 75)
  - Field Directory, 1968-1973 (Box 2:, Folder 76-80)
  - Field Education, undated (Box 2:, Folder 81-83)
    - Directory, 1973-1976 (Box 2:, Folder 84-85)
    - Manual, 1968-1969 (Box 2:, Folder 86-87)
    - Instruction Manual, 1968-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 88-90)
    - Placements, 1950-1951 (Box 2:, Folder 91)
  - Financial Aid, 1973-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 92)
  - Fulltime Faculty and Staff, 1946-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 93)
  - German, Carel—Acting Dean, 1971-1972 (Box 2:, Folder 94)
  - Goldstein Memorial Lecture, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 95)
    - Announcement, 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 96)
  - Grant booklet, 1974-1975 (Box 2:, Folder 97)
  - Guidelines for Student Research of new Field Placement, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 98)
  - Hartford Courant—New School of Social Work, 1945 (Box 2:, Folder 99)
  - Hartford Council on Social Agencies, Study of Agency Interest in School of Social Work, 1944 (Box 2:, Folder 100)
  - Hathway, Marion Lecture, 1949 (Box 2:, Folder 101)
  - Hearing on Complaints procedure, 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 102)
  - Highlights of School Conference with Dr. Fowler, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 103)
  - Historical Approaches [Trecker], undated (Box 2:, Folder 104)
  - Increment Policy, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 105)
  - Insights [Student newspaper], 1961-1964 (Box 2:, Folder 106)
  - Interviews, undated (Box 2:, Folder 107)
  - Juvenile Delinquency Seminar, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 108)
  - Letter from Pres. Jorgenson—Board Approval for School, 1942 (Box 2:, Folder 109)
  - Letter—Energy Crisis, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 110)
  - Library
    - Cuts in Budget, 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 111)
    - Library committee, undated (Box 2:, Folder 112)
    - Handbook for Periodical listing, undated (Box 2:, Folder 113)
    - School of Social Work Library plans, 1946 (Box 2:, Folder 114)
  - Life in Cities—Special program, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 115)
  - Lutz, Werner (Dean), 1968-1971 (Box 2:, Folder 116)
    - Proposal for School reorganization, 1970-1971 (Box 2:, Folder 117)
  - Massoth, Leona—Executive Secretary, American Association of Schools of Social Work, Study of Need for School Average, 1944 (Box 2:, Folder 118)
  - Student Strike, 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 119)
  - Summer Training for Welfare and Youth services, 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 120)
  - Meeting of Field Work supervisors, 1949 (Box 2:, Folder 121)
  - Memoranda
    - Field Agencies, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 122)
    - Organization of Field Education, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 123)
    - Research Center, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 124)
    - Theory Practice Seminar, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 125)
  - Mental Health Institute, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 126)
  - Minutes
    - Faculty meeting, 1974-1975 (Box 2:, Folder 127)
    - Institute Committee, 1950 (Box 3:, Folder 128)
    - Professor Advisory committee, 1948-1950 (Box 3:, Folder 129)
    - Meeting with Board of Trustees about 1380 Asylum, 1949 (Box 3:, Folder 130)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 3:, Folder 131)
  - Master's of Social Work degrees, 1948-1973 (Box 3:, Folder 132)
  - National Association of Schools of Social Work, undated (Box 3:, Folder 133)
    - Programs at School, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 134)
  - National Association of Black Social Workers, undated (Box 3:, Folder 135)
  - New England Regional School, undated (Box 3:, Folder 136)
  - Certification in Social Work Practice Program, 1969 (Box 3:, Folder 137)
  - Open Hearing on Issue of Incompletes, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 138)
  - Orientation, 1970-1975 (Box 3:, Folder 139-140)
  - Probation and Parole Institute, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 141)
  - Procedures from Tenure and Promotion, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 142)
  - Professional Education workshops, 1952-1954 (Box 3:, Folder 143)
  - Progress report on School development, 1946 (Box 3:, Folder 144)
  - Questionnaire of Advising, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 145)
  - Questionnaire to Students re: Field Placement, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 146)
  - Reaccreditation, undated (Box 3:, Folder 147-150)
    - Preparation, undated (Box 3:, Folder 151)
    - Memorandum, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 152)
  - Registration report, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 153)
    - Theory-Practice seminars, 1969-1975 (Box 3:, Folder 154)
  - Reimers, John [first Dean], 1946 (Box 3:, Folder 155)
  - Research
    - Abstracts, 1974-1975 (Box 3:, Folder 156)
    - Center, undated (Box 3:, Folder 157)
    - General, undated (Box 3:, Folder 158)
    - Projects, 1973-1975 (Box 3:, Folder 159-161)
  - Resolutions of Appreciation Staff and University leaders, undated (Box 3:, Folder 162)
  - Rough material on Enrollment and Faculty, 1946-1974 (Box 3:, Folder 163)
  - Salary issues and concerns of the faculty, 1970 (Box 3:, Folder 164)
    - Increase in annual salary rate, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 165)
    - Salary schedule, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 166)
  - Schedule and Registration materials, 1974-1975 (Box 3:, Folder 167-168)
  - School Agency Relationships in Social Work Education, 1949 (Box 3:, Folder 169)
  - School Calendar and Schedules, 1973-1974 (Box 3:, Folder 170-171)
  - School committee, 1969-1970 (Box 3:, Folder 172)
  - School Development plan, 1956-1966 (Box 3:, Folder 173)
  - School manuals, 1968-1969 (Box 3:, Folder 174)
    - Newsletters, 1962-1976 (Box 3:, Folder 175-178)
  - School of Social Work
    - Seminar, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 179)
    - UConn Chronicle, 1973 (Box 3:, Folder 180)
  - Social Action Task Force, 1970 (Box 3:, Folder 181)
  - Social Work Education, Hollis Taylor report, 1952 (Box 3:, Folder 182)
  - State Committee of Professional Education for Social Work, 1939 (Box 3:, Folder 183)
  - State Welfare Department, undated (Box 3:, Folder 184)
  - Statement by Pres. Jorgenson re: School of Social Work, 1950 (Box 3:, Folder 185)
  - Student activism—Vietnam War, 1969 (Box 3:, Folder 186)
  - Student Advising process, 1947 (Box 3:, Folder 187)
  - Student Affairs committee—annual report, 1969-1970 (Box 3:, Folder 188)
  - Students on Extended Degree program, 1973-1974 (Box 3:, Folder 189)
  - Student Handbooks, 1966-1977 (Box 3:, Folder 190-192)
  - Student Participation in School Administration, undated (Box 3:, Folder 193)
  - Summer Session courses, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 194)
  - Training grants, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 195)
    - Training seminar, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 196)
  - Trecker, Harleigh B. [third Dean], 1951-1968 (Box 3:, Folder 197)
    - Remarks at School Dedication, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 198)
    - Resignation, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 199)
    - Speeches to students, 1956-1968 (Box 3:, Folder 200-208)
    - Speeches to Agencies, 1959 (Box 3:, Folder 209-210)
  - Tuition, 1949-1950 (Box 3:, Folder 211-212)
  - University committees
    - Develop Curriculum of School of Social Work, 1942 (Box 3:, Folder 213)
    - Study the Establishment of School of Social Work report, 1943 (Box 3:, Folder 214)
  - University of Connecticut Law School Dedication, 1964 (Box 3:, Folder 215)
  - Conference on Professional Social Work Education, 1949 (Box 3:, Folder 216)
  - Report of Undergraduate committee, 1970 (Box 3:, Folder 217)
  - Weekly Calendars, 1970 (Box 3:, Folder 218)
- Series II: Writings, undated, 1939-1981
  - Social Work Administration, undated (Box 4:, Folder 219-221)
  - Goals for Social Welfare, undated (Box 4:, Folder 222-223)
  - Social Group Work Methods, undated (Box 4:, Folder 224-225)
  - Citizen Board at Work, 1968-1969 (Box 4:, Folder 226-233)
  - Excerpts from The Supervision of Informal Education, undated (Box 4:, Folder 234)
  - Group Work in the Psychiatric Setting, undated (Box 4:, Folder 235)
  - How to Work with Groups, undated (Box 4:, Folder 236)
  - Group Process in Administration, Revised, undated (Box 4:, Folder 237)
  - Social Group Work—Principles and Practice, undated (Box 4:, Folder 238)
  - Group Process in Administration, undated (Box 4:, Folder 239)
  - Master set of writings, 1939-1971 (Box 5:, Folder 240-249)
  - Articles, 1944-1964, 1979-1981 (Box 6:, Folder 250-251)
  - Speeches, 1946-1964 (Box 6:, Folder 252-253)
  - Master's Thesis, ca. 1938 (Box 6:, Folder 254)
  - Notes, undated (Box 6:, Folder 255)
- Series III: Research Studies, undated
  - Ad Hoc committee on Public Welfare (Box 7:, Folder 256)
  - Detroit Study (Box 7:, Folder 257)
  - Executive Role with Board (Box 7:, Folder 258)
  - State and Governor's Committee on Human Services (Box 7:, Folder 259-262)
  - Use of Group Methods (Box 7:, Folder 263)
  - Group Services in Public Welfare (Box 7:, Folder 264)
  - Knox County Survey (Box 7:, Folder 265)
  - Lighthouse Study (Box 7:, Folder 266)
  - Los Angeles Youth Project (Box 7:, Folder 267)
  - Meriden Recreation Study (Box 7:, Folder 268)
  - National Council on Social Welfare Committee on Conferencing (Box 7:, Folder 269)
  - Northern Delaware Study (Box 7:, Folder 270)
  - Palama Settlement Study (Box 7:, Folder 271)
  - Social Agency Boards
    - Exploratory Study (Box 7:, Folder 272)
    - Viewed by Board Members (Box 7:, Folder 273)
  - Springfield Study (Box 7:, Folder 274)
  - Waterbury Study (Box 7:, Folder 275-276)
- Series IV: Research Files, undated, 1921-1964
  - Action Report (Box 8:, Folder 277)
  - Administration/Management (Box 8:, Folder 278-286)
  - Aging (Box 8:, Folder 287-291)
  - Cities (Box 8:, Folder 292)
  - Community (Box 8:, Folder 293-297)
  - Community Action Program (Box 8:, Folder 298)
  - Community/Community Leadership (Box 8:, Folder 299-301)
  - Computers (Box 8:, Folder 302)
  - Crime (Box 9:, Folder 303)
  - Council on Social Work Education (Box 9:, Folder 304-307)
  - Child Welfare League of America (Box 9:, Folder 308)
  - Eagleton Institute (Box 9:, Folder 209)
  - Education (Box 9:, Folder 210-211)
  - Family (Box 9:, Folder 212-213)
  - Family Welfare Association of America (Box 9:, Folder 214)
  - Girl Scouts/Camp Fire Girls (Box 9:, Folder 215-217)
  - Conference with Governor on Welfare Department, 1959 (Box 9:, Folder 218)
  - Governor Ribicoff (Box 9:, Folder 219-220)
  - Governor's Task Force on Housing (Box 9:, Folder 221)
  - Government Consolidation (Box 9:, Folder 222)
  - Government Printing Office (Box 9:, Folder 223-227)
  - Greater Hartford Program (Box 9:, Folder 228)
  - Handicapped (Box 9:, Folder 229)
  - Head Start (Box 10:, Folder 230)
  - Health/Recreation (Box 10:, Folder 231-234)
  - Health, Education and Welfare [Health and Human Services] (Box 10:, Folder 235-240)
  - Institutes—Schools/Private (Box 10:, Folder 241-243)
  - Institute of Industrial Relations (Box 10:, Folder 244-245)
  - International Conference on Social Work (Box 10:, Folder 246)
  - Jewish Welfare (Box 10:, Folder 247-248)
  - Judge Baker Foundation (Box 10:, Folder 249-250)
  - Juvenile Delinquency (Box 10:, Folder 251-253)
  - Law (Box 10:, Folder 254)
  - Mental Health (Box 10:, Folder 255)
  - Mental Health (Box 11:, Folder 256-257)
  - Mental Retardation (Box 11:, Folder 258-262)
  - Unidentified (Box 11:, Folder 263)
  - Monographs (Box 11:, Folder 264-266)
  - Moynihan Articles (Box 11:, Folder 267)
  - National Association of Social Workers (Box 11:, Folder 268-271)
  - National Conference on Social Welfare (Box 11:, Folder 272)
  - National Federation of Settlements and Neighborhood Centers (Box 11:, Folder 273)
  - National Resources Committee (Box 11:, Folder 274-276)
    - Planning Board (Box 11:, Folder 277-278)
  - National Social Welfare Assembly (Box 11:, Folder 279)
  - Periodicals (Box 12:, Folder 280-281)
  - Police, Cities (Box 12:, Folder 282)
  - Poor (Box 12:, Folder 283)
  - Population (Box 12:, Folder 284-285)
  - Poverty (Box 12:, Folder 286-287)
  - Prisons (Box 12:, Folder 288-289)
  - Private Institutions (Box 12:, Folder 290)
  - Program Budgeting (Box 12:, Folder 291)
  - Rehabilitation (Box 12:, Folder 292)
  - Social Casework reprint (Box 12:, Folder 293)
  - Social Groups (Box 12:, Folder 294-303)
  - Social Services News (Box 12:, Folder 304)
  - Social Services Review (Box 12:, Folder 305)
  - Social Work Education (Box 13:, Folder 306-315)
  - Social Work, General (Box 13:, Folder 316-320)
    - Historical documents, 1921, 1939, 1959-1964 (Box 13:, Folder 321-322)
  - Stevenson, Adlai (Box 13:, Folder 323)
  - School of Social Work Theses (Box 13:, Folder 324-325)
  - Volunteers (Box 13:, Folder 326-328)
  - Welfare (Box 13:, Folder 329)
  - Welfare (Box 14:, Folder 330-336)
  - Works Progress Administration (Box 14:, Folder 337-339)
  - Youth (Box 14:, Folder 340-346)
  - Board Member Institute—Dayton, Ohio (Box 15:, Folder 347)
  - Houston Travelers Aid Society (Box 15:, Folder 348)
  - So...You Serve on a Board—Pasadena, California (Box 15:, Folder 349)
  - Role of Community Health and Welfare Councils (Box 15:, Folder 350)
  - 25th Board of Members Institute—Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies (Box 15:, Folder 351)
  - Albany Board Members Institute (Box 15:, Folder 352)
  - Institute for Board Members—Richmond School of Social Work (Box 15:, Folder 353)
  - Board Member Institute—Council for Spartanburg, South Carolina (Box 15:, Folder 354)
  - Springfield Area Leisure Time Services Study (Box 15:, Folder 355)
  - More Power to You—Akron, Ohio (Box 15:, Folder 356)
  - Institute on the Orientation of New Board Members—Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 15:, Folder 357)
  - Gearing Services to Community Changes—Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 15:, Folder 358)
  - Board of Management—Springfield YMCA (Box 15:, Folder 359)
  - Kit—Federation of Jewish Philanthropies (Box 15:, Folder 360)
  - Board Member Institute—Waterbury, Connecticut (Box 15:, Folder 361)
  - Steps toward Broader Board Leadership—Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies (Box 15:, Folder 362)
  - Wars of the Instant Medicines (Box 15:, Folder 363)
  - Greater Hartford Community Council Questionnaire (Box 15:, Folder 364)
  - Memorandum to Members of the Connecticut Association of Mental Health Board of Directors (Box 15:, Folder 365)
  - Volunteer Board Study Committee—United Fund of Greater Lowell (Box 15:, Folder 366)
  - Workshops (Box 15:, Folder 367)
  - Board and Committee Members—Leadership Resources (Box 15:, Folder 368)
  - Newsletter—Girl Scouts, 1958 (Box 15:, Folder 369)
  - Board Members Manual—Harley-Slamon Schild Guidance Clinic (Box 15:, Folder 370)
  - Being Wise on Membership—PTA Magazine (Box 15:, Folder 371)
  - Nominating for Elective Office—Girl Scouts (Box 15:, Folder 372)
  - Policy Mailing (Box 15:, Folder 373)
  - Board and Executive Directors—YWCA (Box 15:, Folder 374)
  - Study of Board—Executive Relationships in Five Family Agencies, David Tanenbaum (Box 15:, Folder 375)
  - Community School and Its Administration (Box 15:, Folder 376)
  - On the Administration of the Voluntary Social Agency, Hans Falch (Box 15:, Folder 377)
  - Volunteer-Staff Relations, David Austin (Box 15:, Folder 378)
  - Memorandum to Board Members—National Social Workers Association (Box 15:, Folder 379)